Hoffman Family Papers
© 2006 University of Connecticut
- Series IV: Government Documents, undated, 1965-1980
  - Police Reports (2), undated, [1. police profiles of YIP activists (late 1967 or 1968); 2. letters to NYCPD concerning police brutality at the Rusk demonstration; 3. NYCPD arrest report from the demonstration against Rusk, black-out, contains Hoffman's name; 4. letters to NYCPD concerning police brutality at Rusk demonstration from the NYCLU; 5. NYCPD report concerning Operation Breakthrough; 6. NYCPD chronological report on Hoffman's activities; 7. NYCPD document from April 27 demonstration calls for photo and audio surveillance, includes section on Hoffman; 8. letter to NYCPD concerning police brutality at Columbia University; 9. NYCPD file on SDS actions in fall 1968, Hoffman mentioned as organizer; 10. 5th Avenue Vietnam Peace Parade Committee newsletter containing a GI's protest letter; 11. NYCPD report on a YIP counter-recruitment demonstration 1968; 12. Society of African American Policemen commendation letter to the Nation Of Islam; 13. miscellaneous paper mentions Dave Delligener and Foley Spruce; 14. Assigned to Commanding Officer Bureau of Special Services, NYCPD report on a Crazies demonstration against the New York Times; 15. NYCPD document concerning security for the Waldorf Astoria June 1969; 16. Commanding Officer Bureau of Special Services to Chief Inspector, NYCPD report of demonstration and arrest of Hoffman April 7th 1969; 17. unidentified agent or agency, report on the new MOBE meeting, includes Hoffman; 18. list of registrations; 19. NYCPD file photos of Hoffman 1970; 20. NYCPD report of the Progressive Labor Party (PLP) faction of SDS demonstration March 24 1970 in which they denounce Hoffman; 21. NYCPD report on a YIP Be-In March 26 1970, looking for Hoffman; 22. NYCPD document lists Hoffman's activities; 23. NYCPD report on 5th Avenue People's Peace Committee protest for the Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.); 24. NYCPD document on the cocaine arrest; 25. NYCPD document notes Hoffman as a fugitive] (Box 4:132)
  - Government, undated, [1. New York City FBI, orders to Boston FBI to investigate Hoffman; 2. Washington Field Office FBI, report on Hoffman appearance at Georgetown University (?) Symposium; 3. Chicago FBI, document Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.) contempt of court sentencing procedure; 4. Chicago FBI, document concerning Hoffman contempt of court charge; 5. unidentified agent or agency, report of Hoffman's conduct at O'Hare airport; 6. unidentified agent or agency, report of Hoffman's speech at Washington State University concerning the Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.) trial; 7. unidentified agent or agency, FBI report of Hoffman's speech at Mid-Peninsula Free University; 8. New York City FBI, leads and orders to Boston FBI concerning Hoffman fugitive investigation] (Box 4:133)
  - Government, 1965, [1. unidentified agent or agency, Hoffman is looking for a place to sleep] (Box 4:134)
  - Government, 1967, [1. appendix from Hoffman's profile - Black Panther Party (BPP) and SDS; 2. New York City FBI, document details Hoffman's activities, "Death of Money"; 3. New York City FBI, document details Hoffman's activities in YIP; 4. New York City FBI, document summarizes arrests; 5. Chicago FBI, Hoffman's activities in 1968, focuses on plans for trip to Prague; 6. unidentified agent or agency, report of interview with a witness of the Democratic National Convention (DNC) protests in 1968] (Box 4:135)
  - Government, 1968 (1), [1. New York City FBI, report on YMCA camp for the Democratic National Convention; 2. New York City FBI, report on SDS, East Side Service Organization (ESSO), Liberation News Service (LNS), press conference for National Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam, Socialist Scholars Conference, Close the Pentagon March; 3. New York City FBI, Chicago 7, Revolution for the Hell of It, Rubin, Congress on Racial Equality (CORE) and Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) mentioned; 4. New York City FBI, report on Steal This Book, Yip-Out, YIP to defend Colorado students, May 24 1968 demonstration at St. Marks (FBI report), Festival of Life, Yip-In plans for the DNC, illegal travel to Vietnam in: World from the Left; 5. Chicago FBI to Director, Hoffman's "revolutionary statement" sent to the Washington Field Office FBI; 6. news articles - New York Daily News, Washington Daily News, New York Times, flag desecration; 7. Boston FBI to New York City FBI and Director FBI, under surveillance at Sheila's home in November 1968 in Cambridge, MA; 8. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, charged with concealed weapon - new hearing to charges dismissed; 9. New York City FBI, demonstration at HUAC with information on SDS and YIP activities; 10. appendix - Militant Labor Forum, National Committee to Abolish HUAC, National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, National Lawyers Guild, Socialist Workers' Party, SDS, Du Bois Club (CPUSA); 11. cover sheet on information on National MOBE in preparation for a press conference 9/27/68, information to be distributed to 108th Military Intelligence Group, Second OSI District, NISO, Secret Service, United States Attorney Southern District New York, United States Attorney Eastern District New York] (Box 4:136)
  - Government, 1968 (2), [1. Chicago FBI, document details Hoffman's activities at the DNC, plans for Prague, quotes from demonstrations and speeches, and information about his arrest at O'Hare Airport for a concealed weapon; 2. Chicago FBI to New York FBI and Director FBI, arrested crime aboard aircraft, carrying a concealed weapon; 3. Chicago FBI, Hoffman conviction in ant-riot law case; 4. Chicago FBI, report on an interview with Hoffman in the Chicago American; 5. New York City FBI, report on Yip-Out and general activities of Hoffman and Rubin; 6. unidentified agent or agency, Region 1, 113th Military Intelligence Group reports on Hoffman and others conducting police brutality training in Lincoln Park and Chicago PD details further Hoffman activity Lincoln Park; 7. New York FBI Hoffman interviewed by the FBI about YIP plans for the DNC; 8. unidentified agent or agency, Hoffman plans to come to Chicago without a permit, appears on WIND radio; 9. unidentified agent or agency, transcript of appearance on John Madigan's "At Random" Show May 11th-12th 1968; 10. New York City FBI, Hoffman proclaims he is dedicated to the overthrow of the United States government on "At Random"; 11. New York City FBI to Director FBI, COINTELPRO - profile of typical New Leftist (NL), NL organizations in New York City with list of leaders (Rudd, Rosen, Rubin, Hoffman, Jones, etc.), distribution of false letter from 'concerned alumni' about SDS activities, students arrested during Columbia University uprising to have postcard mailed to parents advertising a drug party, flyers printed with "worst of the hippy set" to disrupt SDS, mentions articles in Associated Press that slander Mark Rudd, news article - Guardian by Mark Rudd; 12. New York FBI to Director FBI, COINTELPRO - prepare anonymous mailing to ridicule Hoffman, continue counterintelligence against SDS and widen split, disrupt Student Mobilization Committee, widen split in Liberation News Service, create split between black power movement and NL, false leaflets distributed to discredit Columbia University and Fordham SDS, letter to Life Magazine against Paul Krassner editor of the Realist; 13. New York City FBI to Director FBI, report on Hoffman's activities at Columbia University; 14. New York City FBI, Hoffman arrested during clearing of buildings during Columbia University student strike; 15. New York City FBI, summary report of Hoffman] (Box 4:137)
  - Government, 1968 (3), [1. New York City FBI to Director, basic information on Hoffman - second sheet has alterations to the profile; 2. Chicago FBI, detail YIP intentions at the DNC with underground paper articles and speeches from Hoffman; 3. Chicago FBI, description of events at the DNC; 4. Chicago FBI, witness account of DNC; 5. news article - Chicago Daily News, The Yippies are Coming; 6. Chicago FBI, Hoffman on WIND radio; 7. Chicago FBI, arrest for obscenity by Chicago PD; 8. Chicago FBI, speech in the Chicago Park; 9. Chicago FBI, surveillance reports from the DNC; 10. Chicago FBI, interviews surrounding the Chicago 7 (et. al.) case; 11. appendix - SDS; 12. San Francisco FBI to Director FBI, COINTELPRO - new left photo list, notes on meeting, cover sheet; 13. unidentified agent or agency to New York City FBI, arrest author of interview with Hoffman; 14. New York City FBI to Director FBI, disseminate information to 108th MI Group, Second OSI district, NISO, Secret Service, U.S. Attorney Southern District New York, U.S. Attorney Eastern District New York, Washington Field Office; 15. appendix - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee; 16. unidentified agent or agency, document details the death of Dean Johnson during the DNC 9-18-68; 17. Director FBI to New York City FBI, request for Village Voice article 9-19-68; 18. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman arrested in Chicago for concealed weapon aboard an airplane 9-19-68 -- Director FBI to New York City FBI and Boston FBI, information concerning Chicago FBI letter; 19. New York City FBI to Director FBI, document concerning civil liberties violations at an anti-HUAC demonstration; 20. Director FBI to Secret Service, Hoffman profile; 21. San Francisco FBI to Director FBI, San Francisco FBI is informed of surveillance at DNC; 22. New York City FBI, Hoffman "My Life to Live" in New York Free Press and Liberation News Service; 23. New York City FBI, YIP and Up Against the Wall Motherfucker plans for the DNC, detailed description of DNC events; 24. appendix - Guardian, National Lawyers Guild, SDS; 25. FBI document - Hoffman summary, includes information on Diggers, SDS, DNC, Columbia University strike, HUAC, Black Panther Party (BPP), MOBE] (Box 7:138)
  - Government, 1968 (4), [1. Chicago FBI to New York City FBI and Director FBI, concealed weapon incident report; 2. New Haven FBI to Director FBI, summary of concealed weapon incident; 3. Chicago FBI, summary of concealed weapon incident, Hoffman's Prague plans; 4. New York City FBI, interview with Hoffman concerning DNC along with his official record, profile with record of pre-1960 incidents; 5. Chicago FBI; document details Hoffman's activities at the DNC, plans for Prague, quotes from demonstrations and speeches, and information about his arrest at O'Hare Airport for a concealed weapon; 5. Boston FBI, Hoffman profile; 6. New York City FBI, surveillance at NMC meeting; 7. New York City FBI to Director FBI, distribution of false leaflet, list of activities of the Youth Service Agency and Operation Hippie; 8. New York FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman's connections to the Youth Service Agency, ties to YIP and the Columbia University student strike; 9. Attorney General to Director FBI, DNC and revolutionary statement] (Box 7:139)
  - Government, 1969 (1), [1. Chicago FBI, transcript of Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.) press conference at the Federal Building in Chicago 11-13-69; 2. news article - Liberation Magazine, review of Revolution for the Hell of It; 3. Philadelphia FBI to Director FBI, alerted informants but unable to locate Hoffman's speeches; 4. Chicago FBI, transcript of appearance on "At Random"; 5. Detroit FBI to Director FBI, cover of television transcripts; 6. Boston FBI to Director FBI, report of speeches at Harvard University, Brandeis University, and Concord - report on funding for Steal this Book; 7. appendix - BPP, Liberation Magazine, Militant Labor Forum, National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, National Lawyers Guild, Progressive Labor Party (PLP), SDS; 8. news article, Los Angeles Free Press review of Revolution for the Hell of It; 9. Chicago FBI, report on YIP Chicago 7 (Dellinger et.al.) press conference at Federal Building 11-12-69; 10. New York City FBI, spelling variations on Hoffman's name; 11. New Haven FBI, report of speeches at University of Hartford with a news article from Hard Times; 12. Director FBI to Washington Field Office (WFO) FBI, Hoffman at Concord; 13. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, transcript of appearance on the Irv Kupcinet Show] (Box 7:140)
  - Government, 1969 (2), [1. Minneapolis FBI, transcript from appearance at North Dakota State University; 2. Cincinnati FBI, notes from appearance at Rio Grande College; 3. Chicago FBI, Alexandria FBI, Richmond FBI, Director FBI, concealed weapon aboard an aircraft documents - Hoffman interview with FBI - profile summary; 4. New York City FBI to Director FBI, document on Revolution for the Hell of It; 5. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, tapes from Lipton (Lost Angeles Free Press); 6. Chicago FBI, report on YIP Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.) press conference at Federal Building 11-12-69; 7. appendix - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, National Lawyers Guild] (Box 7:141)
  - Government, 1969 (3), [1. New York City FBI, administrative report concerning New Haven FBI, Chicago FBI, New York City FBI, Washington DC FBI, Boston FBI; 2. Milwaukee FBI, San Francisco FBI, Baltimore FBI, college visit reports; 3. Chicago FBI to Director, report on "impromptu press conference" held at O'Hare Airport; 4. New Haven FBI, report on speech at unidentified university; 5. Seattle FBI, report and transcript of speech at Gonzaga University; 6. Buffalo FBI to Chicago FBI, Hoffman present at State University of New York at Buffalo for symposium on drugs; 6. New York City FBI, document on Hoffman's appearance on "At Random"; 7. New York City FBI, Hoffman is arrested on weapons and narcotics charges, news article - New York Daily News; 8. Detroit FBI, transcript of appearance on Lou Gordon Show, appendix - BPP, SDS, and Minutemen; 9. Chicago FBI, report on Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.) press conference at Federal Building 12-22-68] (Box 7:142)
  - Government, 1969 (4), [1. Indianapolis FBI, report on speech at St. Joseph's University, with transcript; 2. Chicago FBI to Director FBI and New York City FBI and WFO FBI, report on ties between SDS and Chicago 7 (Dellinger, et. al.); 3. Cleveland FBI, transcript of Hoffman's appearance on Allen Douglas Show; 4. Cincinnati FBI, report on request for Hoffman to speak at Antioch College; 5. appendix - Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), BPP, National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee] (Box 7:143)
  - Government, 1969 (5), [1. Chicago FBI. transcript of Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.) press conference at Blackstone Hotel 9-22-69; 2. Cincinnati FBI, transcript of Rio Grande College speech; 3. Philadelphia FBI to Director FBI, report on Woodstock Nation and Army Field Manual; 4. Chicago FBI, transcript of Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.) press conference at the Federal Building 10-2-69; 5. Chicago FBI, transcript National Lawyer's Guild speech on Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.) 10-17-69; 6. New York City FBI, report on Hoffman's financing from book royalties and speeches; 7. New York City FBI to Chicago FBI, Newark FBI, Washington Field Office FBI via Washington DC FBI, Director FBI, Domestic Intelligence Division, protests in Washington DC, interview with reporter with the Star Ledger (Newark) reporter] (Box 7:144)
  - Government, 1970 (1), [1. Chicago FBI, Rubin and Dave Dellinger (Dellinger et. al.) found guilty of conspiracy; 2. SAS, excerpts from speech at Moorhead; 3. New York City FBI, Hoffman and SDS at a Panther 21 protest; 4. New York City FBI, news article on Hoffman's monetary gains from New York Post; 5. Kansas City FBI, document on preparing for speech at Kansas University - speech cancelled after arrest for blowing his nose in the American flag; 6. Attorney General to Director FBI, appeal of flag desecration conviction; 7. Chicago FBI, charges on concealed weapon aboard an aircraft are dropped; 8. Cleveland FBI, surveillance on 11/20/70; 9. unidentified agent or agency, speech on Political Repression at Pittsburg University; 10. FBI profile - biography, activities, public appearances, writings, revolutionary statements, appendix - BPP, Liberation Magazine, Militant Labor Forum, SDS, PLP, Youth Against War and Fascism (YAWF), World Workers Party (WWP), National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee; 11. Chicago FBI, Washington, DC FBI, New York City FBI, Hoffman's future plans] (Box 7:145)
  - Government, 1970 (2), [1. Chicago FBI, Hoffman asks permission to travel to Canada; 2. Kansas City FBI, appearance at Kansas State University is in doubt; 3. New York City FBI, Hoffman returns to New York on 12/17/70 as a self-employed writer; 4. news article - New York Post, Rubin and Hoffman dispute within YIP; 5. unidentified agent or agency, speech at University of Maryland with Rennie Davis, flyers and information on court martial of soldier also appearing, appendix SDS and PLP; 6. FBI, news articles, clash with students at University of Houston and Rice University, information on college lectures; 7. New York City FBI, transcript of Hoffman on the David Frost Show, appendix - BPP; 8. New York City FBI to Chicago FBI and Director FBI, notes on speech at St. John's University; 9. R.L. Shackelford to C.D. Brennan, COINTELPRO, exacerbate split between Rubin and Hoffman, flyer; 10. Chicago FBI to New York City FBI, testimony at Chicago 7 trial; 11. Chicago FBI, Hoffman wants to go to Cuba; 12. Alexandria FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman arrives at airport; 13. Chicago FBI, transcript of Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.) news conference at the Federal Building 2-5-70; 14. San Antonio FBI to Director FBI, COINTELPRO, FBI agents attempt to prevent lecture at University of Texas by distributing harmful information; 15. COINTELPRO, want to disrupt BPP, SDS, Hoffman sent to 108 Military Intelligence Group, Naval Investigation Service Office, Office of Special Investigation in United States Air Force, United States Attorney General South District New York and United States Attorney General East District of New York, Secret Service] (Box 7:146)
  - Government, 1970 (3), [1. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman and Rubin to Europe, Hoffman profile; 2. Chicago FBI to Director, message concerning Hoffman to Legat in Ottawa; 3. New York City FBI, CBS censors Hoffman's shirt, transcript from Merv Giffin with news articles; 4. Chicago FBI, Hoffman to serve 15 day sentence for contempt of court; 5. Minneapolis FBI, Moorhead College speech coversheet; 6. Chicago FBI, verdict and interview with news article New York Times; 7. Chicago FBI, lawyer conference; 8. Chicago FBI, Rubin and Hoffman in New Haven in support of Bobby Seale; 9. Director FBI, Hoffman full file (two copies)] (Box 7:147)
  - Government, 1970 (4), [1. Albany FBI, surveillance at Skidmore College, appendix - BPP and SNCC; 2. Secret Service, search for Hoffman 4/24/70; 3. New York City FBI, flight to Rome; 4. New Haven FBI to Director FBI, notes from appearance at Trinity University; 5. Director FBI, document from profile states Hoffman is emotionally unstable; 6. unidentified agent or agency, Rubin and Hoffman motion to court for travel to Europe; 7. New York City FBI, biography, summary of appearances and actions from 5-5-70 to 10-25-70; 8. San Diego FBI, speech at San Diego State College transcript] (Box 7:148)
  - Government, 1970 (5), [1. Denver FBI to Chicago FBI and Director FBI, speech at Colorado State University with transcript; 2. unidentified agent or agency, news articles - Quicksilver Times, Hatchet (George Washington University), American University, Evening Star, general information concerning DNC, marches, etc.; 3. Chicago FBI, indictment papers for Chicago 7 (Dellinger et. al.); 4. Chicago FBI, Hoffman guilty of 23 criminal counts of contempt, with transcript] (Box 7:149)
  - Government, 1971 (1), [1. Oklahoma City to New Orleans FBI, New York City FBI, San Francisco FBI, and Director FBI; Hoffman leaves Oklahoma for Washington, DC; 2. Director FBI to New Orleans FBI, prepare for Hoffman, Washington, DC FBI to Chicago FBI, New York City FBI, and Director FBI, Hoffman's indictment; 3. Oklahoma City to Director, transcript of speech at Oklahoma University about plans for protest in Washington, DC and People's Peace Treaty; 4. New York City FBI, Hoffman arrested in for inter-state riot following Washington, DC protests; 5. New York City FBI to Chicago FBI and Director FBI, notes of speech at Mamaroneck High School in New York City; 6. San Juan FBI, Hoffman requests permission to travel to Virgin Islands; 7. unidentified agent or agency, May Day protests; 8. New York City FBI, Hoffman has his nose broken at Washington, DC protest and repaired in New York City; 9. unidentified agent or agency to Secret Service in New York City, Hoffman writes I Quit in Virgin Islands; 10. Cleveland FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman at Kent State University, summary of speech with surveillance; 11. unidentified agent or agency, Weiner - "Pirate Editions Rip-off" (possibly COINTELPRO document); 12. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman to travel to Canada for speaking tour and book deal; 13. New York City FBI, biography 1-22-71 to 5-13-71] (Box 7:150)
  - Government, 1971 (2), [1. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman approved to travel to Europe; 2. Director FBI, document claims Hoffman is emotionally unstable; 3. New York City FBI to Washington Field Office FBI, all new leftists are armed and dangerous; 4. Assistant Attorney General Internal Security Division to Director FBI, electronic surveillance of Hoffman requested; 5. Chicago FBI, transcript of Hoffman appearance on Underground News 5-14-71; 6. New York City FBI, transcript of Hoffman appearance on Paul Benzaquin Show 7-30-71; 7. news article - Washington Post, court overturns flag desecration conviction; 8. Cleveland FBI, surveillance chart 9-13-71; 9. Oklahoma City FBI to Director FBI, press conference in Oklahoma City about Washington, DC protests and People's Peace Treaty; 10. Oklahoma City FBI, transcript from speech at Oklahoma University; 11. Oklahoma City FBI, travel plans to Washington, DC; 12. New York City FBI to Chicago FBI and Director FBI, report on Steal This Book; 13. Attorney General to Director, arrest on 5-5-71 for inter-state riot; 14. news article - New York Post, Hoffman's arrest on riot charges; 15. New York City FBI to Director FBI, Chicago FBI, Omaha FBI, St. Louis FBI, Washington Field Office FBI, arrest documents; 16. New York City FBI, news article - New York Post, Hoffman breaks nose; 17. Cleveland FBI, transcript from appearance on Alan Douglas Show; 18. San Francisco FBI to Director FBI, travel information from Oklahoma City, discusses interviews with stewardesses; 19. Oklahoma City FBI, surveillance at airport; 20. Director to Legat Ottawa, travel to Canada is barred, biography with a focus on Canada; 21. New York City FBI, summary of trial proceedings in inter-state riot case; 22. New York City FBI, Hoffman retires from politics in Jamaica] (Box 7:151)
  - Government, 1971 (3), [1. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, transcript of appearance on Howard Miller Show; 2. Chicago FBI to Director FBI, Chicago will look into 1/28/69 conviction; 3. Milwaukee FBI to Director FBI, Hoffman will appearance at Lawrence University with Young Lords, SDS, and BPP; 4. Philadelphia FBI to Director FBI, transcript of appearance at Political Repression Conference at Pittsburg University, copies sent to Army Intelligence, Secret Service, OSI, United States Attorney Pittsburg, NISO Pittsburg; 5. unidentified agent or agency, surveillance of Hoffman in Virgin Islands, changes name to Frank Edward Crosetti; 6. New York City FBI, biography on Hoffman with corrections from Washington, DC FBI and updated to reflect time in Virgin Islands] (Box 7:152)